RESUME



Data Scientist with strong statistical background and 3+ years of experience in Machine Learning, database management and creative thinking to solve real business problems, working mainly for Google projects. Double Master's Degree in advanced statistics with R and SQL and Business Intelligence.

CURRENT POSITION

Data Scientist

EXPERIENCE

Data Scientist Team Leader

Fujitsu CSL, 2018/09 - now

- Customer volume forecasted using neural networks.
- Classificatory system created to improve the distribution and performance of agents (PCA) and clustering techniques)

OK Google App Developer

Sigma Technologies, 2016 - 2018

- Supervisor of the voice sample proofreading giving feedback on the speech recognition
- Speech recognition accuracy greatly improved for American Spanish and Catalan.

Research Fellow

Guttmann Institute, 2015 - 2017

- Therapy created from scracth based on 15 years of clinical data.
- Non-parametric methodology used to choose the best therapeutic techniques.

EDUCATION

Big Data & Business Intelligence

European Business School of Barcelona, 2018 - 2019

- Master Thesis: Marketing Plan for an online wine shop
- marketing plan designing, SEO positioning or KPI selection methodology.

Applied Statistics with R

Rey Juan Carlos University, 2017 -2018

- Supervised and unsupervised techniques using R and SQL with all the statistical foundations
- Robust and non-parametric techniques.

Neurorehabilitation pre-PhD program

Autonomous University of Barcelona, 2015 - 2017

- Pre-doctoral course using R and SPSS
- Experience in one of the most important european laboratories.

Neuropsychology

University of Valencia, 2009 - 2013

- Knowledge centered on applied statistics
- Studies based on critical thinking and the scientific method.

CONTACT

- ♥ Tokyo, Japan
- □ +81 080 7793 6892
- ✓ dvallslanaquera@gmail.com
- github.com/dvallslanaquera
 - **y** @Standby_00

TECHNOLOGIES

</> R

</>
Python

</> Google Apps Script

SQL

Tableau

₽ Git

FIELDS OF KNOWLEDGE

x² Machine Learning & Version Control

LANGUAGES

English

Japanese

Spanish

☆☆☆☆☆☆☆☆☆

Q Catalan **☆☆☆☆☆☆☆☆☆**

Q Italian
